euppublishing.com 2019-05-23

# 

Edinburgh University Press Ltd is a wholly owned subsidiary of the University of Edinburgh. Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at [dpo@ed.ac.uk](mailto:dpo@ed.ac.uk "DPO email"). This privacy policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you. We are fully committed to complying with the General Data Protection Regulation and will do our utmost to protect the information you provide to us.

### What information do we collect about you?

We collect information about you when you publish with us, register on our website, place an order or use products and services. We also collect information when you sign up to our newsletters and our blog, use free access tokens and provide feedback. Website usage information is collected using cookies (view our Cookie Notice further down this page). 

### Explaining the legal basis we rely on:

The law on data protection sets out a number of different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data, including:

Consent

In specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent. For example, when you tick a box to receive email newsletters.

Contractual obligations

In certain circumstances, we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.

For example, if you order an item from us for delivery, we’ll collect your address details to deliver your purchase, and pass them to our supplier. 

Legitimate interest

In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business. For example, when you become a member of a society that includes a journal subscription. 

### How will we use the information about you and with whom will we share it? 

When you publish with us:

We will use your information in order to implement the terms of the publishing contract. This includes passing your details to external reviewers, copy editors, typesetters, printers and agents working on behalf of Edinburgh University Press. Some of the information you provide will be available in the published product. 

When you register an account with us:

When you register with us, you will need to enter your name, email address and provide a password. We will use this information to provide service requests such as table of contents and citation alerts, activate online subscriptions, use free access tokens, open ebooks you have purchased, access inspection and review copies and to manage your account. You can delete your account at any time.

When you order books and journals from us:

The information you supply to us when you purchase books and journals will be used to process your order. We will pass this information on to our service providers to pick and supply the products.

When you sign up to our subject mailing lists:

We will contact you about products and services we think may be of interest to you, or blog posts that have published only if you have given us your consent to do so by signing up to our mailing lists or blog site. You can withdraw this at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email or emailing [marketing@eup.ed.ac.uk](mailto:marketing@eup.ed.ac.uk "marketing email").  

When you subscribe to journals:

We will use your information to process your subscription order and provide subscription services.

Where journal subscriptions are part of a membership of a society, we are processing your information on behalf of that society and we will share your information with that society.

Where journal subscriptions are included as part of a conference fee, the organisers will supply your information to us so that we can process your subscription and set up access as necessary.

When you apply for a job with us:

We will use the information you provide during the application process will only for the purpose of progressing your application, or to fulfil legal or regulatory requirements if necessary. 

### How long will we hold your information? 

We will only keep records of your personal information for as long as you wish to hear from us or for as long as the contract requires.

### Rights available to individuals

You can request or update the information we hold on you by logging into your account or contacting us [dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk](mailto:dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk "Data Protection Email").

You have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at any time if you feel there is a problem with the way we are handling data. More information can be found here: <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/> 

### Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page. Please check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes we make.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site or server; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the information it holds, please contact [dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk](mailto:dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk "Data Protection Email"). 

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from our web server to your browser. It is stored on your hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites, and will not damage your system. If you would like to know more about cookies please visit [www.ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/online/cookies/](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/online/cookies/ "ICO Cookies").

### How do we use cookies on euppublishing.com?

Web traffic analysis

Cookies help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalized service. They enable us to:

• estimate our audience size and usage pattern;

• store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customize our website according to your individual interests;

• to speed up your searches

Edinburgh University Press Ltd use cookies to show us which areas of the site are popular and those that are not often visited, thus enabling us to use our website resources in the most effective way. We do not use them to identify you specifically.

We use session cookies to keep you logged in for the duration of your visit, to enable you to complete transactions on this website and, for example, to pre-populate forms with information to save you keying in data that you have already provided.

We use permanent cookies to record basic web traffic analysis using Google Analytics and to remember you on your return to euppublishing.com and edinburghuniversitypress.com.

Email communications

Edinburgh University Press Ltd uses cookies in its email communications via Dotmailer to track whether that communication has been opened and read, and whether the recipient has used the onward links contained in the email. This allows us to monitor and improve our email communications.

### What we do not use cookies for

Edinburgh University Press Ltd cookies do not analyse visits to other websites. We do not use cookies for any third-party activities (other than JetPack for our WordPress Blog, Google Analytics & Dotmailer as described in this document), or to insert any contextual advertising.

### How can you manage the use of cookies on this website?

You can reset your browser to refuse cookies or alert you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept cookies, some features of this site might not work as intended (e.g. services accessed while logged in, and all transaction/checkout facilities). We do not use cookies to identify you personally, except when you opt to use the logging in facility.

### Links

Our website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible and cannot accept any liability for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be cautious when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects your personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the Edinburgh University Press Ltd website.

### Contact us

If you have any questions about this cookie notice or the information it holds, please contact [dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk](mailto:dataprotection@eup.ed.ac.uk "Data Protection Email").
